I'm from Teika University.
我是帝華大學來的
Welcome. Please proceed to the front entrance.
歡迎，請直接開到大門
Yes. Okay.
是，好的
Understood.
我知道了
They're here.
他們來了
Right, understood. I'm on my way.
好，知道了，我現在過去
They've entered the building.
他們進來了
Listen up! We only have five minutes!
聽好了，我們只剩五分鐘
Tojo University Hospital.
東城大學附屬醫院
Known in the Tokai region,
雖然在東海地區非常知名
but barely recognized on a national scale.
但以全國規模來看仍不見經傳
But today, from the towering heights of Tokyo,
但今天，位於東京的帝華大學 卻來到我們這裡探查敵情
the giants of Teika University are here on reconnaissance.
該校可是在國立醫院中稱雄的
Professor Nishizaki, we welcome you.
西崎教授，歡迎您大駕光臨
It is my wish to learn all I can from your university.
我今天會盡我所能向貴院學習
A great doctor as yourself? Don't be silly.
您可是帝華大學的大教授 真是太謙虛了
What business do they have with a small regional hospital like ours?
國立一流的大學醫院 怎麼會到我們這種地方小醫院呢？
Teika University, with its cutting-edge cardiac surgery technology…
帝華大學擁有最先進的心臟外科技術
THE RACE FOR CARDIAC GLORY
（心臟外科的頂點之爭）
…and Tojo's own skilled surgeons
與東城大學醫術精湛的外科醫師
are in fierce competition.
正在激烈競爭
The cardiac surgery department where I work
所以在我實習的心臟外科
attracts patients from all over Japan, and even the world,
吸引了許多日本各地… 不，是世界各地的患者
seeking the expertise of Dr. Seigo Saeki.
來尋求佐伯清剛教授的高超醫術
There's one more reason for the competition.
兩所大學競爭的另一個理由是
The approaching elections for the Chairman of the Surgical Society.
日本綜合外科學會 即將舉辦理事長選舉
Professor, it's time.
教授，時間到了
To earn the position to stand at the top of 40.000 surgeons
這個位於四萬名外科醫生之上的位置
Tojo's Dr. Saeki and Teika's Dr. Nishizaki
據說將由東城大學的佐伯教授 和帝華大學的西崎教授
go head-to-head.
兩人一爭高下
It's unclear why,
雖然不知道原因為何
but today,
但有一位患者瓣膜嚴重損壞
they will perform surgery on a patient
並患有糖尿病 和腎功能不全等全身疾病
who suffers conditions usually deemed to be ineligible for surgery.
一般情況下不可能進行手術
They've come to watch us fail, I presume.
我想他們此行 是想親眼見證我們的失敗吧
Dr. Saeki has risen to the challenge.
不過佐伯教授接受挑戰
For Tojo University, failure is not an option.
對東城大學來說 這場手術只許成功，不許失敗
Dr. Saeki's operation will begin shortly.
佐伯教授的手術快開始了
Would you kindly fill me in
能讓我看看佐伯教授
on the tools he will be using?
使用什麼樣的器具嗎？
Much obliged.
沒問題
Give us a close-up of the surgical tools.
請近拍手術器具
Okay.
好
Those are Dr. Saeki's…
那就是佐伯教授的…
black forceps.
黑色止血鉗
Here's the doctor.
教授進手術室了
The heart-lung machine is functioning well.
人工心肺機運轉正常
You got this far in 20 minutes. Dr. Yokoyama, you've improved.
只花了20分鐘，橫山，你進步了
Thank you.
謝謝
Don't stop the heart.
心臟不用停
The Saeki Method on this case?
他要用佐伯式手術嗎？
I thought he would stop the heart.
我還以為會讓心臟停止
We will now proceed with the on-pump mitral valve surgery.
現在開始進行 體外循環心臟二尖瓣手術
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir.
-開始吧 -是，醫生
-Debakey. -Here.
-血管鑷 -是
Cooley hook to Dr. Yokoyama.
把庫里鉤給橫山
-Metz scissors. -Here.
-組織剪 -是
The method that shook the world.
這就是震驚全世界的手術方式啊
The Saeki Method.
佐伯式手術
Unlike traditional heart surgery that stops the heart,
與傳統上使用人工心肺機 讓心跳暫停後再進行的手術不同
it is performed while the heart is still beating.
是在心臟保持跳動的情況下進行手術
It reduces the time needed,
能夠大幅縮短手術時間
and it is easier on the patient.
並大量減輕病患的負擔
It's also said to be a hundred times more difficult.
不過這也比傳統方法難上一百倍
He's able to apply stitches
心臟還在跳動的情況下
while the heart continues to beat.
他居然還能進行縫合
Incredible.
真是厲害
Yes?
喂？
Here's the Solulact.
輸液拿來了
-Call Dr. Saeki. -Okay.
-呼叫佐伯教授 -是
You'll be okay. We've administered the IV.
你不會有事的，我們幫你打點滴了
All ready. Don't worry.
都準備好了，別擔心
Excuse me, miss.
打擾了
-Hayata. -Yes.
-早田 -是
All set.
可以了
Mr. Miyazaki has experienced an aortic dissection.
特別觀察室的宮崎先生 好像出現主動脈剝離
He's scheduled for tomorrow.
他是教授預計明天要動手術的病患
Miyazaki? His tissue is weak. Take him to Operating Room three.
宮崎先生的組織太脆弱了 把他送到第三手術室
-I'll go there soon. -You're going to operate?
-我這邊結束後就過去 -您要幫他開刀？
This surgery lasts three more hours. Should we ask someone else?
這台手術還需要三小時 要不要請別的醫生處理？
We have visitors today. Don't make a fuss.
今天有客人來訪，別亂了陣腳
Dr. Yokoyama, you go. Take over until I get there.
橫山，你先過去 我到之前交給你處理
Understood. This is a crucial operation for you.
好的，這台手術對教授來說至關重要
-Leave it to me. -Thanks.
-那邊交給我吧 -嗯
-Dr. Kakitani, be the lead assistant. -Yes, sir.
-垣谷，你來當第一助手 -好的
-Hayata. -Yes?
-早田 -是
Prepare the intercom and monitor for Room three.
準備第三手術室的對講機和監視器
Dr. Yokoyama is my supervisor,
橫山醫生是我的指導醫生
and as Dr. Saeki's top pupil,
也是佐伯教授的得意門生
he is expected to take his place.
有望成為他的第二把交椅
Did you get the pump? Pick up the pace.
幫浦拿來了沒？動作快點
Dr. Sera, go help in Operating Room three.
世良，你去第三手術室幫忙
Understood.
好的
What's all the fuss? Did something happen?
怎麼吵吵鬧鬧的？出事了嗎？
No problem at all.
一點都沒有
Please observe Professor Saeki's operation.
請繼續欣賞佐伯教授的技術
-We're here. -You're late.
-我們來了 -你來晚了
-Forgive us. -Get the valve.
-抱歉 -去拿人工血管
-Yes, sir. -You two, camera on.
-是 -你們兩個，裝鏡頭
Right.
好
Get Dr. Saeki on the line.
接到佐伯教授那邊
Understood. Excuse me.
是，失禮了
-We're at 24 milliliters. -You're connected now.
-24公釐的準備好了 -連上線了
This is Dr. Yokoyama. Take a look.
我是橫山，請看這邊
We've halted circulation.
剛剛停止循環了
-So, it was an aortic dissection. -All right.
-果然是主動脈剝離 -是的
Scalpel.
手術刀
Dr. Saeki is monitoring a second surgery as he performs his own.
佐伯醫生一邊動手術 還能一邊監控另一台手術
He's superhuman.
真是神乎其技
Observe.
請看
There's a tear in the ascending aorta.
升主動脈出現破裂
-Replace it, Yokoyama. -Understood.
-橫山，做置換手術 -好的
We'll now apply prosthesis.
我們這邊要植入人工腱索了
-It's on you. -Understood.
-那邊就交給你 -是
-Intercom. -Right away.
-對講機 -馬上處理
-Monitor off. -Okay.
-關掉監視器 -好
-Sound up.
-提高音量
-And now the real fun begins. -Right.
-好戲正要開始 -好
Suction.
抽吸
Be careful with the Cooley hook. Yes, like that.
庫里鉤要小心，對，像那樣
Next, we perform the aortic replacement.
接下來要進行主動脈置換
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir!
-開始吧 -是！
It's PSVT.
是陣發性心律過速
-Should we halt the operation? -Calm down.
-手術要暫停嗎？ -冷靜點
We'll continue like this.
繼續這樣進行
Continue the surgery? With heart contractions like that?
心臟這樣收縮了，還要繼續開刀？
You don't need to worry.
您不必擔心
Dr. Saeki does not make mistakes.
佐伯教授不會犯錯
He knows exactly what he's doing.
他完全知道自己在做什麼
No mistakes, you say?
你說從不犯錯？
It's a matter of discipline.
這全是他自己鍛鍊出來的
Dr. Saeki is the only man on earth who's able to perform the Saeki Method.
佐伯醫生是世界上 唯一能夠執行佐伯式手術的人
The only one.
舉世無雙
How's Dr. Yokoyama doing?
橫山醫生還好嗎？
We should be getting a signal from the doctor.
教授應該會給他指示
May I be excused for a moment?
我能暫時離開一下嗎？
Aortal replacement complete.
主動脈置換完成
-Reduce blood flow. -Right.
-降低血流量 -好
Blood flow reduced.
降低血流量了
Blockage removed.
移除阻隔
The heart is beating again.
恢復自主心跳了
-Transfusion! -We need albumin.
-輸血！ -需要白蛋白
Can we stop the heart?
要不要讓心跳停止？
I was given orders to perform aortal replacement. It should be fine.
教授要我做主動脈置換，應該沒問題
Can we contact the doctor?
要聯絡教授嗎？
He's in the middle of surgery.
他正在手術中
Transfusion, hurry.
快點輸血
-Interns, transfusion. -Okay!
-實習醫生，去拿血袋 -好
Stop the blood! More gauze!
快止血，拿紗布來
It's not there. Go to the transfusion room.
不在那裡，去輸血部拿
-Four packs of RBC. -Got it!
-紅血球四袋 -好
Miwa.
美和
Get the Cooley hook.
準備庫里鉤
The Cooley hook?
庫里鉤？
This is not the time to sleep.
現在不是睡覺的時候
Wake up.
快點起來啊
-Room three! -Right!
-第三手術室 -好
Dr. Saeki in operating room one.
佐伯教授在第一手術室
In room three…
而第三手術室
-More! More! Hurry! -All right!
-再拿來，快點！ -是！
Where is it leaking from? Here?
到底是哪裡出血？在哪邊？
Where's my transfusion?
血袋呢？
That's what's going on.
原來是這樣
-Transfusion is ready! -Hurry!
-準備好要輸血了 -快點
There's no pressure. We're losing blood.
血壓沒有回升，一直失血
There's too much blood! I can't locate the source!
出血量太大了，找不到出血點
This is Dr. Saeki's patient. If you let him die…
這是教授的病患，要是救不回來…
Do you think I don't know that?
你以為我不知道嗎？
We have to call the professor.
我們得打給教授
We can't let Teika University see what we've done here!
不能讓帝華大學的人 知道這裡的狀況！
I'm sorry!
抱歉！
-More suction! -Okay!
-繼續抽吸 -是！
It's ventricular fibrillation!
心室顫動
Get me the DC.
準備直流電
-Right away.
-是
Nekota…
貓田
The tubes, hurry.
快點拿配管
Should we call… him?
要打給他嗎？
-He can't be trusted. -But…
-不能相信他 -可是…
He's the only one who can help us!
只有他能幫我們
You know what will happen if we rely on a man like that.
你明知道依賴那種人會發生什麼事
A man like that?
那種人？
Who are you talking about?
你在說誰啊？
-If it means getting the help we need-- -Quiet!
-現在也只能找他幫忙… -別說了！
Stay back, Intern!
實習醫生給我退下
Nekota, the Cooley hook.
貓田，庫里鉤拿來了
Nekota! I have no use for that!
貓田，我不需要那個
Tokai…
渡海
Who called him?
誰打給他的？
Was it you?
是你嗎？
-Gown. -Yes, right.
-手術服 -是
Out of my way.
礙事
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
You're not needed here. Get out!
這裡不需要你，出去！
Why have you only done an aortal replacement?
你為什麼只做了升主動脈置換？
Come on, tell me.
說啊，為什麼？
-Orders from Dr. Saeki. -Is that so?
-這是佐伯教授的指示 -是嗎？
Was leaving a tear in the base of the heart
那留著心臟底下的破裂不管
an order as well?
也是教授的指示嗎？
What the hell are you saying?
你在說什麼鬼話？
Are you saying there has been a mistake?
你是說教授弄錯了嗎？
A big mistake.
大錯特錯
It was the monitor.
問題在於監視器
He was only looking at the ascending aorta,
他只看到升主動脈
and he missed this tear at the base of the heart.
所以漏掉了底部的破裂
He's right. I can't see it.
他說得對，畫面看不到
That why he gave the orders…
難怪教授給了置換的指示…
The problem lies with the surgeon who has continued operating,
問題在於主刀醫生繼續動手術
blindly following orders without checking
盲從指示，卻完全沒有
for damage at the base of the heart.
檢查心臟底部的破裂
Did you just want to save face?
你就只是為了顧面子嗎？
Instead, your foolish mistake has made the situation much worse.
沒錯，你愚蠢的錯誤讓問題更加嚴重
This is what happens when ignorant doctors take up the knife.
讓無知的醫生執刀，就是會這樣
Pay me ten million and I won't tell a soul.
給我一千萬，我就替你保密
You're kidding.
開什麼玩笑？
Ten million? You must be kidding me!
一千萬？你開什麼玩笑
You better resign.
你就辭職吧
Hand over your severance pay
用退職金來付
and I'll make all this disappear.
我會幫你處理並且保密
We still have ventricular fibrillation!
病患還在心室顫動
You're running out of time.
快來不及了
Doctor…
醫生
-Doctor! -I know!
-醫生 -我知道
Help me… I'm begging you…
幫幫我，我求你了
Let's reconstruct the base.
開始修復底部
-Clamp. -Here you go.
-阻斷鉗 -這裡
-You're in my way. -Sorry.
-礙事 -抱歉
-Electroscalpel. Prosthesis. -Yes, sir.
-電燒刀、人工血管 -是
Reconstruction complete. Remove occlusion.
重建完成，移除阻斷
The heart is beating.
心臟恢復跳動了
Good. Next.
很好，繼續
We'll perform on-pump mitral valve surgery.
進行體外循環二尖瓣手術
-You with the glasses. -Yes.
-戴眼鏡的 -是
You don't mean the Saeki Method?
你該不會要做佐伯式手術吧？
-Debakey forceps. Cooley hook. -Right away.
-血管鑷、庫里鉤 -馬上來
-Can you pull it off? -How should I know?
-你辦得到嗎？ -不知道
But for ten million yen,
但為了一千萬日幣
I'll give it my best shot.
我會全力以赴
-Pardon me. -Okay. Let's begin.
-不好意思 -好，開始吧
There was only one man capable…
原本舉世無雙的技術
and now there could be two.
現在可能有兩個人做得到
Metz scissors.
組織剪
-Metz. -Here.
-組織剪 -這裡
-Removing heart-lung machine. -Okay.
-移除人工心肺機 -好
-Black forceps, please. -Yes, sir.
-請給我黑色止血鉗 -是
Black forceps?
黑色止血鉗？
The special surgical forceps that Dr. Saeki uses to finish operations.
佐伯教授手術收尾時 一定會用的特殊止血鉗
It's like a ritual.
就跟儀式一樣
It means the operation was a success.
這代表手術成功了
Dr. Kitajima, go tell the family.
北島，去通知病患家屬
Tell them that Dr. Saeki used the black forceps.
跟他們說佐伯教授用了黑色止血鉗
I'm off to Operating Room three.
我要去第三手術室了
-I'll leave you to stop the bleeding. -Right.
-止血的部分交給你 -好
Three hours and ten minutes.
三小時十分鐘
-Faster than usual. -Yes.
-比平常快 -是啊
He's like God himself.
他簡直是神
Ten million yen it is.
那就一千萬囉
You can finish up.
你可以收尾
Move it.
礙事
-Take over. -Okay.
-接手 -好
-Take these off. -Right.
-這個拿掉
Two hours and fifty minutes…
兩小時又五十分
Tokai.
渡海
That was truly something.
真是了不起
I couldn't replicate it if I tried.
就算我想模仿也做不到
A dangerous operation like that…
像那樣的危險手術…
Director Moriya, we'll discuss things later.
守屋院長，我們之後再談
Right.
好的
Until next time.
那就下次見
Thank you very much.
非常感謝您
Dr. Saeki is indeed a skilled surgeon.
佐伯教授確實是技術高超的外科醫生
But he's just a small-town craftsman.
但他充其量只是個地方職人罷了
A man like him can't be entrusted with the future of Japanese medicine.
日本醫療的未來不可能交給那種人
I'm counting on you, Dr. Takashina.
我就靠你了，高階
Understood.
我知道了
So Dr. Yokoyama's transfer was because of that operation?
橫山醫生因為那次手術而調職嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
He was your mentor.
所以你的指導醫生
But now, you'll be working with Dr. Tokai.
從橫山醫生變成渡海醫生了
-This way. -What?
-跟我來 -什麼？
-As for Dr. Tokai… -Yes?
-渡海醫生…
He's in that room. In fact, he lives there.
他在那個房間裡，其實他是住在那裡
It's our nap room.
那是我們的休息室
But since Dr. Tokai moved in, it's like he's made it his own room.
但是渡海醫生來了之後 那裡好像就變成他的房間了
Excuse me.
打擾了
Pardon me.
不好意思
What is it?
什麼事？
Taking a nap?
來睡覺的嗎？
No, I…
不，我…
You were in the operating room the other day.
你那天也在手術室裡
-I was. -I'm Dr. Sera. An intern.
-對 -我是實習醫生世良
What kind of person is Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生是什麼樣的人？
It's incredible that he was able to save that patient.
他成功救了那個病患，真是太厲害了
And using the Saeki Method…
而且他還用佐伯式手術
-Taking money-- -Are you going to quit too?
-但是收錢… -你也要辭職嗎？
Unskilled doctors are better off dead.
沒技術的醫生還不如死一死算了
Dr. Tokai, I…
渡海醫生，那個…
-About Dr. Yokoyama's patient-- -Out of my way.
-橫山醫生的病患… -礙事
It's a patient handover request.
是關於病患交接的事項
Move it.
礙事
Your physician, Dr. Tokai…
新的主治醫生渡海
He's busy today and he won't be able to see you.
他今天很忙，所以無法來看您
I see.
這樣啊
My first patient. Ms. Taeko Minagawa.
這是我的第一位病患皆川妙子
Her husband died young. She has no family to visit her.
她的丈夫年輕早逝 也沒有家人能探望她
Diagnosed with mitral regurgitation,
因為患有二尖瓣閉鎖不全症
she has to undergo surgery by Dr. Saeki.
將由佐伯教授為她開刀
Ensuring her peace and comfort
確保病患有良好的狀態
is my duty, above all.
是我的工作
It's almost time for your check-up.
差不多要檢查了
-Here's the machine. -Thanks.
-機器在那邊 -謝謝
-I'll take this. -What?
-這個我收走了 -什麼？
What is this thing?
這是什麼？
-It's the new examination machine. -What?
-新的檢查機器 -什麼？
Dr. Tokai has asked us to use this from now on.
渡海醫生要我們以後都用這個
Wait a minute.
等一下
Hold on. What?
等等，什麼？
-Don't you know how to use it? -I…
-你不會用嗎？ -我…
It's no good.
不行啊
It's the new trial equipment Dr. Saeki brought in.
那是佐伯教授引進的臨床試驗新機器
He told you, didn't he?
他告訴過你了吧？
Not a word. I'm serious.
沒有，我說真的
I mean it. And then the patients think I'm no good.
真的沒說，結果被病患說不行
You were just unlucky.
你就是運氣差
About Dr. Tokai…
至於渡海醫生
Apparently, his interns are quitting.
顯然他的實習醫生都辭職了
Dropping like flies, one by one.
一個個落荒而逃
My condolences.
請節哀
TOJO UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
（東城大學附屬醫院）
Yes, this is Dr. Sera.
是，我是世良
It's about your operation report from the other day.
你那天的手術報告
-It's awful. -What?
-爛透了 -什麼？
It says here that Dr. Tokai took over operations from Dr. Yokoyama
上面說渡海醫生替橫山醫生接手
and even performed the Saeki Method.
甚至還做了佐伯式手術
-That's right. -Were you even there?
-沒有錯啊 -你在場嗎？
What?
什麼？
They were fixing the conditions for Dr. Saeki to operate. Nothing more.
他們只是為了讓佐伯教授動手術 先修復一些問題，僅此而已
-Isn't that right? -So I heard from Nekota.
-不是嗎？ -貓田是這麼說的
-I'm certain of it. -What?
-真的是這樣 -什麼？
Got it?
懂嗎？
The Saeki Method
佐伯式手術
is Tojo's groundbreaking surgical technique
是東城大學引以為傲 具開創性的技術
proudly featured in the Japan Surgical Journal.
而且刊登在《日本外科期刊》上
And you think
而你認為
a veteran like Dr. Yokoyama was pushed aside
像橫山醫生這樣的老手
by a low-brow surgeon like Tokai?
能被渡海那種庸醫推到一旁？
Impossible.
不可能
No.
不是
It should never be mentioned.
這種事絕對不可能
Rewrite it.
重寫
Anything can happen in a place like this.
在這種地方，任何事都有可能發生
Dr. Tokai doesn't deal with publications
渡海醫生不寫論文
and he will never be promoted.
所以絕對不可能獲得升遷
As far as rank, he's below even me.
至於地位，他甚至在我之下
-But… -But he's good. The best.
-但是… -他很厲害，是這裡最頂尖的
We have no choice but to follow him when operating.
手術時，我們全都只能聽他的指令
Dr. Saeki knows this too.
佐伯教授也知道
This was supposed to be Dr. Sekikawa's operation.
這台手術本來該由關川醫生主刀
But it's Dr. Tokai doing the work.
結果卻由渡海醫生執刀
I'll now take a pericardial graft.
我要取下心包膜了
-No artificial valves. -Right.
-不要用人工瓣膜 -好的
Not using artificial valves? That's not part of the plan.
不用人工瓣膜？原本不是這樣計劃的
I'll do a valve formation with pericardial graft.
我要用心包膜做主動脈瓣成形術
-I decided so just now. -You can't just…
-我現在決定的 -你不能自作主張
It can heal naturally. There's no use for artificial material.
組織能自然癒合 沒有必要使用人工瓣膜這種異物
Right…
對了
My apologies. You're in charge.
抱歉，主刀的是你
Take over.
換你來吧
-No, continue. -Metz.
-不了，請你繼續 -組織剪
Everyone here looks up to Dr. Saeki,
這裡的每個人都尊敬佐伯教授
hoping to perform the Saeki Method one day.
希望有天自己也能做佐伯式手術
Training tirelessly day after day.
所以日復一日拚命練習
But no one can do it.
但是沒有人辦得到
That Dr. Tokai can do it so nonchalantly…
結果渡海醫生卻輕輕鬆鬆就做到
Who will allow that?
這誰受得了呢？
Countless doctors have quit because of him.
已經數不清有多少醫生 因為他而辭職了
While his skills save patients,
雖然他的醫術能救活病患
he kills doctors.
他卻殺死了其他醫生
That man is the devil himself.
那個人本身就是個惡魔
It was Dr. Tokai's fussing, I presume?
我猜是渡海醫生小題大作了吧？
Dr. Yokoyama's relocation.
我是指橫山醫生的調職
It was his own choice.
那是他自己的決定
Either way, the recent shortage of personnel in cardiac is undeniable.
不管怎樣，不能否認的是 最近心臟外科的人手不足
While patients increase, the turnover rate drops.
病患增加，病床周轉率卻下降了
So there's someone I would like to introduce to you.
所以我想介紹一個人給你
What are you planning?
你在打什麼算盤？
This is Taeko Minagawa. She's scheduled for mitral valve surgery.
這位是皆川妙子 排定進行心臟二尖瓣手術
Dr. Saeki will operate.
將由佐伯教授主刀
Dr. Tokai will assist.
第一助手是渡海醫生
Dr. Kakitani will be second assistant.
第二助手將由垣谷醫生擔任
What's with the tone of voice? The documents are a mess too.
這是什麼語氣？而且資料也亂成一團
-Dr. Saeki oversees this surgery. -Sorry.
-這可是由佐伯醫生主刀的手術 -抱歉
Enough.
夠了
Go over it again with Dr. Kakitani.
再跟垣谷醫生核對一次
You should be up there, not me.
明明就是你該上台的，不是我
The editor-in-chief of the Japan Surgical Journal,
《日本外科期刊》的主編
Mr. Hideto Ikenaga, has requested to observe the operation.
池永英人先生申請要來觀摩手術
In medical academia, publishing in journals
在醫療學術界，在期刊上發表論文
can influence the Impact Factor, which evaluates a doctor's accomplishments.
能得到評估績效的指標“影響因素”
Among these journals, the one that holds great influence
在日本學術期刊中，最有影響力的
is the Japan Surgical Journal.
就是《日本外科期刊》
Its editor-in-chief wields great power, even in elections.
其主編在理事長選舉中 也有非常大的影響力
Dr. Saeki currently leads by six points
佐伯教授是77分
with an Impact Factor of 77, while Dr. Nishizaki follows closely at 71.
西崎教授是71分 目前佐伯教授領先6分
A visit in preparation for the election?
為了理事長選舉所以來訪查的嗎？
This could gain Dr. Saeki significant support.
佐伯教授或許能獲得大力支持
That concludes my report. Professor.
以上是我的報告，教授
Lastly, let me make an introduction.
最後，容我介紹一下
As of yesterday, a new member has joined our cardiovascular department
昨天有位新成員 加入了我們的心臟血管外科
and he is here with us today.
他今天也來到現場
Please come in.
請進
Teika University's own Dr. Takashina.
歡迎帝華大學的高階醫生
He's an excellent doctor who has studied medicine in America.
他赴美學過最先進醫療 是一名優秀的醫生
Due to our staff shortage,
由於我們的人員不足
Director Moriya has sent him to assist us.
守屋院長派他來協助我們
So, Dr. Nishizaki asked for this.
所以是西崎教授的要求啊
Director Moriya will have a spot waiting for him at Teika when he steps down.
他替守屋院長安排了位置 讓他退休後到帝華的系列醫院工作
But why bring a known enemy on board?
但為什麼會讓敵方的醫生加入我們？
I'm Dr. Takashina.
我是高階
I had the opportunity to observe Dr. Saeki's operation
前幾天有幸觀摩了佐伯教授的手術
and I learned a great deal.
我學到了很多
To return the favor to you all,
為了回報各位
I have something to show you.
我也有樣東西想介紹給大家
It's called the "Snipe."
這叫做“醫狙”
It's a new medical device from America and is yet to be used in Japan.
是美國開發的最新醫療儀器 在日本都還沒人使用過
Its main application is mitral valve surgery.
主要用途是在心臟跳動的情況下 進行二尖瓣手術
The goal is the same as the Saeki Method, but the process is quite different.
目的和佐伯式手術一樣 只是過程完全不同
With the flip of a switch, the device can be used by anyone,
只要按下開關，任何人都可以使用
removing the need for a surgeon's careful hand entirely.
完全不需仰賴外科醫生的精湛技術
Dr. Saeki's Saeki Method
佐伯教授的手術方式
allows for the repair of the mitral valve while the heart beats,
是在心臟保持跳動時進行二尖瓣修復
significantly reducing surgery time.
能夠大幅縮短手術時間
Similarly, the Snipe involves inserting a catheter
“醫狙”也是類似的原理
from the tip of the heart
在心臟跳動時
while it continues to beat,
從心臟尖端插入導管
replacing the damaged valve with an artificial one.
在受損的二尖瓣上直接補人工瓣膜
Taking one-third the time of the Saeki Method,
手術時間只有佐伯式手術的三分之一
and removing the need for a heart-lung machine,
也不需要使用人工心肺機
this method is unparalleled in Japanese medicine.
這在日本醫界是史無前例的方法
Do you mean by using the Snipe,
你是說，只要用“醫狙”
the Saeki Method will become unnecessary?
就不需要佐伯式手術了嗎？
I suppose it does.
我就是這個意思
How foolish!
說這什麼蠢話！
Don't make a mockery of Dr. Saeki.
別看不起佐伯教授
He's the best there is!
他是最頂尖的醫生
I have to ask.
我就問一個問題
Just how many people at Tojo University, no, in the world,
東城大學裡，不，全世界有多少人
are able to perform Dr. Saeki's method?
能夠實施佐伯式手術呢？
Correct.
沒錯
Only one.
只有一個人
How useful is that method, then?
那麼這方法再厲害也沒用吧？
The Snipe, however, can be used by anyone.
而這台“醫狙”是人人都能使用
It's equipped with micro-sensors
前端有微型感測器
for automatic targeting of the affected areas.
能自動瞄準患部
Dr. Saeki is indeed praised for his perfectionism.
我相信佐伯教授 毫不失誤的醫術備受推崇
And that's exactly the reason Dr. Saeki is so highly regarded.
所以佐伯教授才會被稱為 世界頂尖的外科醫生
This device allows for precision that is a hundred times greater.
但是這台機器的精準度 是他的一百倍
Humans have their limits.
人類也是有極限的
But technology will continue to evolve forever.
但科技卻能不斷進步
I see now. So that's your plan.
原來這就是你的計畫
You plan to use the Snipe to lure away our patients
你打算用“醫狙”搶走那些
who come here seeking hope from the black forceps.
原本為黑色止血鉗慕名而來的病患
Dr. Saeki is only able to save one, maybe two lives in a single day.
佐伯醫生一天只能救一條命 頂多也就兩條
However, the Snipe can be used by anyone.
但是“醫狙”人人都能使用
Think of the thousands of patients
想想成千上萬的那些病患
eagerly awaiting your care.
急著希望你替他們動手術
They can receive that care right away with the Snipe.
但有了“醫狙” 他們就能立刻動手術
There is no longer a need for the Hand of God.
不再需要什麼神之手了
Geez. Why? What's the reason?
不是，為什麼？是什麼原因？
She just doesn't want surgery.
她就說不想動手術了
-What should we do? -Hospitals are full of surprises.
-我們該怎麼辦？ -醫院真是充滿驚喜
What should we do?
我們該怎麼辦？
Even if the operation does indeed save my life,
就算手術能救我一命
I'm still all alone.
我還是孤單一個人
Even if I continue to live--
就算我活下去…
Don't say that.
不要說這種話
You have a chance here.
您有多麼幸運啊
There are thousands of patients hoping for surgery from Dr. Saeki.
現在有數百名患者 等著佐伯醫生替他們開刀
I suppose that's right.
應該吧
-Yes. -That's right.
-是啊 -沒錯
And why should I care?
但那又關我什麼事？
It's no good.
還是不行啊
Ms. Minagawa, what is it?
皆川女士，您怎麼了？
Ms. Minagawa, are you okay? What's wrong?
-皆川女士，您沒事吧？怎麼了？ -皆川女士
Doctor, your orders.
皆川女士…醫生，請你下指示
-Your orders, please! -Right.
-醫生，請下指示 -好
-Dopamine, please. -Okay.
-請給我多巴胺
-And get Dr. Tokai! -Right away.
-呼叫渡海醫生 -是
-No, get Dr. Kakitani. -He's out right now.
-不，找垣谷醫生吧 -他外出了
-We need a lead doctor. -That's you.
-我們需要負責的醫生過來 -就是你啊
Levels dropping.
數值下降
She's in shock.
她要休克了
Doctor.
醫生
Doctor!
醫生！
Get the respirator!
插管！
-Okay. -Respirator!
-好 -插管
Here.
這裡
Move it.
礙事
Taking over.
我來
It's in. Ambu bag.
插好了，甦醒球
-Take over. Hurry. -Right.
-你來，快點 -是
-Prepare ultrasound. -Okay.
-準備超音波
She needs an antibiotic drip.
給我消毒鋪巾
-Needle, please. -Right.
-針筒給我 -好
Blood pressure stabilized.
血壓穩定了
-Order a CT scan. -Right.
-安排做電腦斷層掃描 -是
-Take it from here. -Okay.
-剩下的交給你了 -好的
You did well today.
你今天做得很好
If that patient had died,
要是病患死了
it would have been the end for Tojo.
東城大學就完了
You are truly serving me well.
你真的為我貢獻了很多
That surgery the other day,
前幾天的二尖瓣手術
was it to save me the burden?
也是為了不給我添麻煩吧？
You, somehow,
沒想到你
pulled off the Saeki Method.
居然能完成佐伯式手術
What?
什麼？
What do you mean?
您是什麼意思？
It doesn't matter.
沒什麼
There is only one man
全世界只有一個人
who can use the black forceps.
能夠使用黑色止血鉗
I often dreamed of it as a kid.
我小時候經常想像
Becoming a doctor, living that life.
成為醫生，過那樣的生活
Saving patients' lives
拯救病人的性命時
with grace, never faltering.
能夠處變不驚、泰然自若
I dreamed of it constantly.
我經常夢到那樣的場景
But despite becoming a doctor…
結果當了醫生之後卻…
That goes
我也…
for me too.
一樣
It's no good.
不行啊
Just like Ms. Minagawa says.
就跟皆川女士說的一樣
Why is the curtain open?
窗簾怎麼拉開了？
What?
什麼？
Speaking of,
說到這個
Ms. Minagawa is always saying…
皆川女士老是說…
It's no good.
不行啊
TAEKO MINAGAWA
（患者姓名：皆川妙子）
What is it, Mom?
媽，怎麼了？
You finally answered.
你終於接了
So, did you get the rice I sent?
收到我寄去的米了嗎？
I got it. It's too much, even if I eat it every day.
收到了，太多了，我每天吃也吃不完
Don't you have someone to enjoy it with?
沒有人陪你一起吃嗎？
No. Just me as usual, unfortunately.
很遺憾，我還是只有一個人吃
How pitiful.
好可憐
After all, you're a doctor.
你好歹也是個醫生
You should be seeing five to six women regularly.
應該要經常左擁右抱 五、六個女人才對
-Why did you become a doctor? -Is that why you called?
-不然你當醫生幹嘛？ -你就是打來講這個？
-I'm hanging up. -Wait a second.
-我要掛了 -等一下
How is Dr. Saeki doing?
佐伯醫生還好嗎？
Your father would be proud.
你爸會以你為傲的
His son is working in the same hospital
兒子跟他之前的同事
as his former colleague.
在同一間醫院工作
Work hard for your old man.
你要連爸爸的份一起加油
Yes.
好
I'll send more rice.
我會再寄米過去
-Wait. -Bye.
-等等 -再見
I live to see another day.
我又活過了一天
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
Ms. Minagawa. Would you please come here?
皆川女士，能請您過來嗎？
Look.
您看
You've been watching that old tree,
您每天都看著那棵老樹
hoping it will bloom, right?
等著它開花，對吧？
Leaving the curtains open all day.
您不論早晚都開著窗簾看
That sakura tree…
那棵櫻花樹
In the year I was born,
聽說在我出生那年
it was the very first to bloom.
第一次開了花
What? You were born around here?
什麼？您在這附近出生的嗎？
My house was just beyond that apartment building over there.
我家就在那棟公寓後面
-I see. -I lived there for many years
-這樣啊 -我在這裡住了好幾年
until I got married and left home.
直到結婚後才搬離開家
That sakura tree and I
那棵櫻花樹跟我
lived during the same time
一起走過了
through the Showa and Heisei eras.
昭和與平成時代
It bloomed beautifully last year, but this year…
去年花開得很漂亮，但今年…
We are at the end of our short lives.
我們短暫的壽命也到了盡頭
I went and had a look.
我去看了一下
It's budding.
已經長出花苞了
It is indeed withering,
雖然有點枯萎了
but it hasn't given up just yet.
但它今年還沒有放棄
This is not the end.
還沒到盡頭
The tree will bloom again.
今年也會開花的
I have to see it through
那我得撐下去
and watch it bloom.
看它花朵盛開的樣子
That's right.
沒錯
Maybe if the tree can do it,
如果那棵樹可以
so can I.
那我也可以
You can.
是的
That's right.
沒錯
The patient was in shock before.
病患曾一度休克
This is not the time to operate.
現在不適合動手術
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Mr. Ikenaga from the Journal is here.
《日本外科期刊》的池永主編要來
Do you think postponing will help us in the election?
手術延期對理事長選舉有幫助嗎？
We'll be seen as irresponsible.
只會被認為我們很不負責任
Operate on a different patient, perhaps?
或許能換一個病患？
I've already forwarded the patient's info to Mr. Ikenaga.
我已經將病患資訊傳給池永主編了
What good is it if the patient dies?
要是患者死了有什麼用？
The Saeki Method will be difficult under these conditions.
以目前狀況來看 很難進行佐伯式手術
But the patient is only going to get worse.
但就算手術延後 病患的情況也只會更糟
At that point, we would have to call it off altogether.
到時候也只能取消手術
Oh, my.
哎呀
This is quite the dilemma.
看來很兩難呢
Dr. Takashina has an idea about Ms. Minagawa's surgery.
關於皆川女士的手術 高階醫生有個提議
He suggests we use the Snipe instead of the Saeki Method.
他認為我們能用“醫狙” 取代佐伯式手術
Using a scalpel would cause too much pain to the patient.
開胸手術會給病人帶來太多的負擔
We can reduce that burden with the Snipe.
而“醫狙”的切口只有區區四公分
-Perfect conditions to use it. -What about permission?
-正好適合使用 -但“醫狙”並沒有
What about the Ministry of Health?
取得厚生勞動省的許可吧？
We must solve that first.
得先解決這點才行
We only need permission from the university's ethics committee.
我們只需要大學的道德委員會許可
Which is led by Dr. Saeki.
委員長是佐伯醫生
Do you plan to play into our weakness and use us as your guinea pigs?
你是打算利用我們的弱點 把東城大學當成白老鼠嗎？
If you're still unsure, should we call it off?
如果還是有疑慮，那就取消手術吧
We couldn't…
那個…
We need to think about prioritiies.
我們應該考慮優先順序
Stubbornly halt the surgery and crush Tojo's reputation,
是要意氣用事，停止手術 打壞東城大學的名聲
or save the patient and break new ground with the Snipe.
還是拯救病人 使用“醫狙”開創新天地
It may indeed bring about the end of the Saeki Method.
以結果來看 這或許會終結佐伯法手術
But using the Snipe is our only option to overcome this problem.
但目前唯一的解決辦法只有“醫狙”
You should consider yourselves lucky to have my help.
有我的幫忙，你們應該覺得慶幸才對
Lucky?
慶幸？
The chance for Tojo University
能夠由東城大學
to introduce this new technology to the world
發表日本首例的全新醫療技術
is a grand opportunity, right?
這是個絕佳的機會，不是嗎？
We would only be assisting the enemy.
這樣只是在幫帝華大學而已
Leaving the surgery to someone else--
讓別人做二尖瓣手術…
We can change the rules, if needed.
如果有必要，可以改變規則
I have a motto.
我有個座右銘
"We must not waste life
“絕不能因為規則的束縛
being bound by petty rules."
而丟掉性命”
I say…
我認為
we accept Dr. Takashina's offer.
可以接受高階先生的提議
We know where our priorities lie.
我們早就知道什麼應該優先了
With our patients.
病患
However, for the sake of our university,
但是對東城大學來說
we must not fail this surgery.
手術絕不能失敗
Dr. Tokai and I will assist.
渡海和我會擔任助手
Don't be ridiculous. Having Dr. Tokai assist is fine.
別傻了，渡海就算了
-But you as well, Dr. Saeki? -It doesn't matter to me.
-但你也要當助手？ -我無所謂
This operation requires no assistance.
反正這台手術不需要助手
Just in case. Got it, Dr. Tokai?
以防萬一而已，渡海，可以嗎？
Doctor's orders.
悉聽尊便
Just one thing.
但我有個條件
If you ask me to take over, even for a second,
如果手術途中需要我來接手
I would like to ask that you submit your letter of resignation.
那麼就請你提交辭呈
What do you think?
你意下如何？
What do you say?
怎麼樣？
Very well.
好啊
But, if I succeed…
但如果我的手術成功
You, Dr. Tokai,
那就請渡海醫生你
will be the one resigning.
提交辭呈
For Tojo's sake.
這也是為了東城大學
Based on what I've heard around,
根據我所聽說的
you're quite the problem child.
你是這裡最會給人添麻煩的醫生
I'll be there.
手術那天我會到
You better be too.
你也一定要到場
In other words, a surgery that normally takes four hours
換句話說，原本的手術要花四小時
will be performed in less than one.
現在的手術不到一小時就能完成
This will greatly reduce the burden on your body.
這能大大減輕您身體的負擔
I see.
這樣啊
If we have your permission,
如果同意
please sign here.
請在這裡簽名
Excuse me.
不好意思
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
Yes?
什麼事？
I would like to ask for your opinion.
我想問問你的意見
-Me? No, I'm not… -Answer her,
-我？我不是… -回答她
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
I think…
我認為…
you should accept.
您應該接受新的手術
You'll do great.
您不會有事的
Have you made up your mind?
您決定了嗎？
Is this the right thing to do?
這是對的做法嗎？
What do you think, Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生，你覺得呢？
Doctor? Doctor.
醫生？醫生
I'm begging you. Say something.
拜託你說點什麼
She's your patient, right?
她是你的病患，不是嗎？
She's your patient!
她是你的病患！
-I'm going to change. -Okay.
-我要去換衣服了 -好
Excuse me. You're an intern, right?
不好意思，你是實習醫生吧？
That's right.
對
My name is Kinoshita.
我叫木下
Clinical trial coordinator.
臨床試驗協調員
How was the new genetics tester?
新的基因測試儀器怎麼樣？
That new machine?
那台新儀器？
-Indeed. -I see.
-沒錯 -這樣啊
CLINICAL TRIAL COORDINATOR
（臨床試驗協調員）
It was a bit confusing at first, but it worked out…
一開始有點搞不清楚 但後來弄懂了…
Thanks for your cooperation.
感謝您的合作
Sure.
不客氣
Will you be going there?
您要進去嗎？
-Yes, for a study group. -Study group?
-對，去參加讀書會 -讀書會？
Pardon me.
不好意思
All this French cuisine…
這些法式料理…
What kind of study group is this?
這到底是什麼讀書會？
A laser scalpel, invented by Daiichi Industries.
為了討論第一重工開發的雷射手術刀
Utilizing an all-new CO2 laser technology,
這運用了全新的二氧化碳雷射技術
allowing for improved incisions.
下刀時能夠更加精準
Just like that.
就像那樣
-Right. I'll try it on a few patients. -Thank you.
-好，我會在病患身上試試 -謝謝
Is it always like this?
你一直都這樣接受招待嗎？
-This is a study group. -"Try it out"?
-這是讀書會 -試試？
Patients are people.
病患是人，不是物品
They're things.
他們就是物品
You…
你…
Don't you have a heart?
你有沒有良心啊？
Does having a heart…
有良心
save lives?
就能拯救人命嗎？
Truly skilled doctors…
醫術精湛的醫生
can do whatever they want.
可以隨心所欲
It's just like what Dr. Takashina says.
高階醫生說得沒錯
People like you shouldn't be doctors.
你這種人不該當醫生
I'm leaving.
我要走了
I'm going home.
我先告辭了
-I have a question. -Yes?
-好，回歸正題 -好的
I would like you to look into something for me.
我想請你幫我查個東西
The fateful day finally arrived, the day of the surgery.
左右許多人命運的那一天 手術日終於到來
This way.
這邊請
Why is Dr. Nishizaki here?
西崎醫生怎麼也來了？
The editor-in-chief requested that he join us.
主編邀請他一起來
Come on… pick up.
快啊，快接電話
This is Taeko Minagawa. Thank you.
這位是皆川妙子，拜託了
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生！
Isn't Dr. Saeki operating?
不是由佐伯醫生主刀嗎？
They'll be revealing a new procedure.
他們將發表新的手術方法
Everyone is here.
大家都到了
Shall we introduce the Snipe?
容我向各位介紹“醫狙”
Snipe?
“醫狙”？
I'm grateful to be given this opportunity.
非常感謝給我這個機會
Surgery is surgery. There is no changing that.
手術就是手術，這點不會變
By the way, there's no sign of Dr. Tokai yet.
對了，怎麼沒看到渡海醫生？
-Dr. Sera! -Where's Dr. Tokai?
-世良！ -渡海先生呢？
He's nowhere to be found.
到處都找不到，也聯絡不上
Forgive us. Dr. Tokai is absent.
抱歉，渡海不在
We're out of time. Dr. Kakitani will assist instead.
沒時間了，讓垣谷當助手
He's a pain in the ass as always.
他一如往常地給人添麻煩了
There's no difference if he's here or not.
反正他在不在都一樣
And now, Case 847.
現在，病例847號
Off-pump mitral valve surgery using the Snipe.
用“醫狙”進行的 非體外循環二尖瓣手術
Dr. Sera. Dr. Tokai wasn't in the other ward.
世良醫生 另一棟病房也找不到渡海醫生
I'll check the nap room again.
我再去休息室找找
Assistance wasn't necessary after all.
的確不需要助手
Why don't you sit back and have some tea?
您何不坐著休息，喝杯茶？
How kind of you.
謝謝
Have you seen Dr. Tokai?
有看到渡海醫生嗎？
-He wasn't there. -Look harder.
-他不在裡面啊 -再更仔細找
-What? -The sofa.
-什麼？ -沙發
-The sofa… -The sofa?
-沙發？
Dr. Tokai! Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生！
-What are you doing here? It has started! -Keep it down.
-你在這裡做什麼？手術開始了 -吵死了
-Are you afraid of losing the bet? -What?
-你怕賭輸嗎？ -什麼？
Are you running away?
你要逃跑嗎？
-What the hell? -Come on. We're going.
-搞什麼？ -快點，得快點過去
NEW MESSAGE FROM KAORI KINOSHITA
（木下香織傳來新訊息）
What is it?
那是什麼？
NOW PRINTING
（列印中）
-Where are you going? -Move it.
-你在做什麼？ -礙事
Nekota, bring the document to Dr. Kurosaki and the professor.
貓田，把文件拿去給黑崎醫生跟教授
-Okay. -Not from me.
-好 -別說我給的
Got it.
知道了
Let us introduce the Snipe.
那麼接下來就請“醫狙”登場
Professor Nishizaki. Let's begin.
西崎教授，那我們要開始了
So that's the Snipe?
那就是“醫狙”嗎？
My pupil brought it back from America.
這是我的徒弟從美國帶回來的
-This was just delivered. -What is it?
-這是剛傳來的 -這是什麼？
Dr. Tokai, hurry!
渡海醫生，快點！
The Snipe has entered the heart's apex.
“醫狙”現在進入心尖
Through the left ventricle.
穿過左心室
Almost at the mitral valve.
快到二尖瓣了
This is Kurosaki. Stop the operation, please.
我是黑崎，請先中止手術
What's the issue?
怎麼了？
I've just received new information on the Snipe.
我剛才收到關於“醫狙”的新資料
According to these documents, a number of problems have occurred
雖然是非公開資料 但美國使用“醫狙”手術的案例中
during Snipe surgeries in America.
發生過意外
Including death.
包含死亡案例
Excuse me. Professor, read this.
打擾了，教授，資料在這裡
This is news to me.
這是我第一次聽說這種事
Dr. Takashina, did you withhold information
高階醫生，你難道刻意
from us and the patients?
向我們和病患隱瞞這件事嗎？
-What's this about? -It's true there have been incidents.
-這是怎麼回事？ -確實發生過醫療事故
We've looked into it.
你們還查得真仔細
Who told you?
資料是誰給的？
Tokai.
渡海
Sorry, I'm late.
抱歉，我來晚了
I see. So this was your doing.
原來如此，這是你幹的好事
-Nurse. -Hayata.
-護理師 -早田
Yes.
是
Why now? We're almost finished here.
現在來做什麼？手術快結束了
I'll take over. Take your little toy and get out.
我會接手，帶著你的玩具出去吧
She has no strength. If we stop now, she'll die.
她快沒體力了 要是現在中止手術，她會死的
The professor and I will take over. There's still time.
我和教授一起動手術就來得及
You plan to do the Saeki Method?
你打算現在用佐伯式手術？
-The Snipe is safer. -That thing has killed people.
-“醫狙”比較安全 -那東西害死過人
This tool has a future in saving thousands of lives.
它未來將能拯救成千上萬人的命
Forget the future. I'm talking about now!
我不管未來怎樣，我說的是現在
The Snipe is her only hope.
“醫狙”是她唯一的機會
It will succeed. I have no doubt.
手術會成功的，我有信心
Continue the surgery.
繼續手術
Use the Snipe.
用“醫狙”
Dr. Tokai, this is Dr. Takashina's operation.
渡海，高階醫生是主刀
I take full responsibility.
我會負全責
-Volume up. -Yes, sir.
-把聲音打開 -是
Let us continue.
手術繼續吧
Professor!
教授！
We're already finished.
手術完成
A new era begins now.
新時代開始了
Professor Nishizaki. We did it.
西崎教授，手術成功了
Excuse me.
打擾了
Dr. Tokai, about the Snipe documents…
渡海醫生，“醫狙”的資料…
It was her, right?
是那個協調員給的吧？
The coordinator you met yesterday.
昨晚為了這個才跟她見面的吧？
Well…
那個…
Are you really going to leave?
你真的會離職嗎？
-Why? -What?
-為什麼？ -什麼？
It will be him who leaves.
要走的是他
What?
什麼？
We saw the Snipe succeed.
我們都看到“醫狙”成功了
You lost the bet.
你輸了賭注
You'll see soon enough.
你馬上就會知道了
Are you awake? The operation is all done.
您醒了嗎？手術完成了
It's a success.
非常成功
You can rest without worry.
請好好休息，不必擔心
Where's Dr. Sera?
世良醫生在哪裡？
Dr. Sera?
世良？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I'm telling you. That old woman is going to die soon.
意思就是，那個老婆婆快死了
What? Why?
什麼？為什麼？
-What is it, Ms. Minagawa? -It hurts…
-皆川女士，怎麼了？ -好痛
-Where does it hurt? -Here…
-哪裡痛？ -這裡
Why do you say that?
為什麼這麼說？
-What do you mean she'll die? -Keep it down.
-她會死是什麼意思？ -吵死了
-What do you mean? -Move it.
-你是什麼意思？ -礙事
This.
你自己看
A rookie like you wouldn't understand.
你這種新手看了也不會懂
-Dr. Takashina. -Hang in there.
-高階他… -撐著點
He didn't do his homework.
並沒有做足功課
-Dr. Sera! -I told you.
-世良醫生 -看吧
-Is Dr. Sera there? -Yes.
-世良醫生在嗎？ -我在
-Dr. Sera! Dr. Sera! -Yes!
-世良醫生… -我在！
You have to hurry. Ms. Minagawa is in pain.
快點，皆川女士說她很痛
Okay.
好
-Call the operating room. -Right!
-通知手術室 -好
-Ms. Minagawa! -It's only a little pain.
-皆川女士！ -只是術後稍微疼痛而已
Painkillers.
止痛藥
-Ms. Minagawa. -Dr. Sera!
-皆川女士 -世良醫生
-Are you okay? -It hurts, doctor.
-您還好嗎？ -醫生，我好痛
Hang in there, Ms. Minagawa.
皆川女士，您撐著點
Ms. Minagawa!
皆川女士！
Dr. Sera…
世良醫生
-What's this? -It's her CT scan results.
-這是什麼？ -她的斷層掃描
An aneurysm?
動脈瘤？
-Her spleen could burst. -It already has.
-有脾動脈瘤破裂的可能性 -已經破了
She has abdominal hemorrhaging.
腹部正在大出血
Ms. Minagawa.
皆川女士
-Call Dr. Saeki! -Right.
-聯絡佐伯教授 -是
-Ms. Minagawa. -A hemorrhage? Why?
-皆川女士 -為什麼會出血？
The operation was perfect.
手術很成功的
On her heart, yes.
心臟很成功沒錯
But that's all you saw.
但你只看心臟
Replacing bad valves with new ones.
置入新的瓣膜取代原先損壞的瓣膜
You should know that it can cause other issues.
你該知道血液循環突然變好 可能會引發其他問題吧
That's why I had to stop you.
所以我當時阻止你了
The case files had a similar story. Death.
有個類似的死亡案例
You saw it, didn't you?
你有看吧？
Before the surgery,
手術前
you saw her CT scan, didn't you?
你確認過她的斷層掃描吧？
You thought it was safe to replace the valves.
然後認為放入新的瓣膜也沒問題
If this woman dies, so do you.
要是她死了，那你也去死吧
I see. But that's your patient.
這樣啊，但那是你負責的病患
I'll leave it up to you.
你自己決定
Is there a problem?
出了什麼問題嗎？
It's nothing.
沒有
Hang in there, Ms. Minagawa.
皆川女士，撐著點
Hang in there.
撐住啊
-Thank you. -Yes.
-拜託了 -好
-Here she is. -One, two, three!
-她來了 -一、二、三
We'll perform emergency surgery.
現在進行脾動脈瘤修復的緊急手術
-What's her blood pressure? -Sixty.
-血壓多少？ -60
-Antibiotics. -Right.
-消毒器具 -是
-Drapes, too. -Okay.
-手術鋪巾
Electroscalpel.
電燒刀
There's too much blood. Suction!
出血太多了，抽吸
More gauze!
再給我紗布！
-Transfusion! -Right!
-準備輸血 -是
-Transfusion! Gauze! -On it!
-輸血、紗布 -馬上來
Bring gauze!
紗布拿來
Damn it. She's losing too much blood!
可惡，她失血過多
-Gauze! -Here.
-紗布 -這裡
Transfusion ready.
輸血準備好了
It's too late.
太遲了
Gauze!
紗布
Blood pressure 50.
血壓降到50了
-Four-zero. -Right.
-4-0號剪 -好
Doctor…
醫生
Doctor!
醫生！
Are you ready to give up?
準備好要放棄了嗎？
Cough up your severance pay
把退職金吐出來
and I'll help.
我就幫忙
What are you talking about? At a time like this!
都這種時候了，你還說什麼鬼話？
Can't you see this? She's losing too much blood.
你看不出來她已經失血過多了嗎？
If we don't stop the bleeding, she'll die!
如果無法止血，她會死的
Then do it yourself!
那你就自己處理啊！
Damn it!
可惡！
Gauze!
紗布！
How much do you want?
你要多少？
What will it take for your help?
多少錢你才願意幫忙？
That woman is my patient.
皆川女士是我的病患
Hoping to see the sakura bloom,
她因為想看到櫻花盛開
she believed me and accepted surgery.
所以選擇相信我，並接受手術
It's my obligation as a doctor to save her.
身為醫生，我有義務要救她
But…
但是…
But, I…
但是我…
I'm a doctor, but I can't do anything.
我只是個無能為力的醫生
As much as it hurts to say, you're the only one who can help.
我很不想承認，但只有你能幫忙了
If it's money that you want, I'll pay for it myself.
如果你要的是錢，我會自掏腰包
I'm begging you. Help this woman.
我求你了，拜託你幫幫她吧
Please!
拜託！
I'm begging you!
我求求你！
We don't have time. You'll help me.
沒時間了，你進來得幫我
He has no surgical experience!
他沒有手術經驗
-I'll do it. -Wash your hands.
-我願意 -去洗手
Yes, sir.
是
I see. So Dr. Tokai is taking over.
這樣啊，渡海醫生接手了
Understood.
我知道了
Forgive me.
請原諒我
-Suction, hurry! -Blood pressure 50!
-抽吸 -血壓50
-A big needle! -Twenty-six.
-大一點的縫針 -26公釐
-Put it in there! -Right!
-快放進去！ -是！
-More suction! -Okay.
-繼續抽吸 -好
-More!
-抽吸 -是
-Metz! Hold this. -Twenty-six milliliters.
-給我組織剪 -26公釐的拿來了
Blood pressure down to 49. Getting lower.
血壓降到49，還在下降中
Doctor, I can't find the wound.
醫生，我找不到傷口
Then why don't you take the whole thing out?
那為什麼不整個拿出來看？
-Hold it. -What?
-拿著 -什麼？
-Hold it! -Yes, sir!
-拿好！ -是！
Hurry!
快點！
Needle.
縫針
-Metz. -Right.
-組織剪 -好
-Bleeding stopped. -Blood pressure stabilized.
-止血了 -血壓穩定了
One hundred million.
一億
What?
什麼？
Until you pay me off,
直到你付清之前
you're stuck here working for me.
你都得待在我底下工作
TOJO UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL FORMER WING
（東城大學醫院，舊館）
TAEKO MINAGAWA
（患者姓名：皆川妙子）
The splenic artery.
脾動脈
You knew, right?
你早就知道了吧？
But you let Dr. Takashina use the Snipe anyway.
但你還是讓高階醫生 用“醫狙”動手術
You expected it all along.
你早就料到事情會這樣發展
I suspect Takashina will lie low for a while now.
我想高階會暫時安分一點了
You've done well, Tokai.
渡海，你做得很好
You truly are
你真的為我…
serving me well.
貢獻了很多
X-RAY FILM MR. TATSUJI IINUMA
（患者姓名：飯沼達次）
CHEST
（攝影部位：胸部）
DOCTOR: ICHIRO TOKAI
（主治醫師：渡海一郎）
Surgery is a gamble.
手術就像賭博
You live or you die.
不是生就是死
I'm scared. Is that wrong?
我很害怕，難道這有錯嗎？
Do it.
你就做吧
You want to prove yourself, right?
你想證明自己，是吧？
Tomorrow…
明天
Japanese medicine will change forever.
日本的醫療將會永遠改變
Will it be me who leaves? Or you?
離開的會是我還是你？
Everything is as I expected.
一切都如我預期
Please come. The patient is fighting for his life.
請跟我來，病患性命垂危
Just quit.
你就辭職
And get out.
然後滾出去
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：林婉婷